musicalchairs.info 2018-12-31

# About musicalchairs - For Classical Music Professionals

This site is owned and operated by musicalchairs.info Ltd (henceforth referred to as "musicalchairs").

As a Company it is extremely important that we give time and thought as to how we acquire personal data, how we store it and how we process it. We must be worthy of the trust that you place in us to handle your data with integrity and security, upholding your privacy and safety.

**GOVERNANCE and CONTACT  
**

Clare Bradbury is the musicalchairs Data Controller. If you have any questions or feedback about privacy, or wish to make a complaint about the way in which we have handled your personal data, please contact clare@musicalchairs.info or phone +44 (161) 2826042. Clare and all other employees at musicalchairs also act as Data Processors, and have had GDPR training.

**DATA THAT MUSICALCHAIRS GATHERS**

Our “customers” comprise our Publishers and our Readership (these groups overlap).

When a customer registers with the site we hold their name, email address, country and date of registration. If they then publish a listing (eg Instrument Sale, Course, Competition, Job, Profile for the public Directory or Stolen Instrument), or subscribe to our Job Alerts, that data is also associated with them in our database.  
These submissions are acquired and processed on the basis of consent.

When an invoice is raised, the Publisher's contact details are acquired. If she chooses to pay via WorldPay or PayPal then these details are shared with those platforms to expedite the payment. We do not hold any Card details. Worldpay acquire the IP address of the payer which they share (unsolicited) with us. We are not responsible for the Data Protection afforded by WorldPay and PayPal - any data that you share with them for the purposes of payment is at your own risk.  
These submissions are acquired and processed on the basis of contract.

**TRANSPARENCY, RIGHTS and ERASURE**

Customers can view all of their data via the website, or by emailing features@musicalchairs.info (we endeavour to reply to data requests within 48 hours). Listings can be taken offline at any time via the website. Readers can unsubscribe to the Job Alert at any time via the website, or by clicking the link at the end of each Job Alert email. Customers who wish to unregister entirely can email features@musicalchairs.info. If they have no listings to their account then we will erase all their details from our servers. If they have published listings then we will delete their name (and other identifying elements) from all relevant records; but for contract reasons we will usually need to maintain a contact email address - if this can identify them (eg john.smith@gmail.com) then we will ask the customer to substitute a new email address of their choice.

**TRACKING**

 _Google Analytics_

When someone visits musicalchairs.info we use Google Analytics to collect internet log information and details of visitor provenance and behaviour patterns. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. _This information is processed in a way which does not identify anyone_. We do not make, and do not allow Google to make, any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website.

_Cookies_

We may place a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer. The cookie itself does not contain Personal Information although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. musicalchairs uses cookies to track user traffic patterns (as described above).  
Readers can refuse cookies by turning them off in their browser. If Readers have set their browser to warn before accepting cookies, they will receive the warning message with each cookie. Readers do not need to have cookies turned on to use this site.

**SHARING OF THE INFORMATION**   
Musicalchairs will not share information about individual users with any third party, except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public.

**LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES**   
We do not have any control over the Privacy settings of websites which we may link to. 

**SECURITY**   
Musicalchairs is proud to employ some of England and Scotland's most skilled programmers to look after our Servers and Networks and who share our commitment to protecting your personal data. And by choosing Mythic Beasts, we have a hosting company that goes the extra mile for your security (https://www.mythic-beasts.com/support/topics/security).

May 2018
